Hello my name is Scott and I'm the owner of Climb On indoor rock climbing gym in Wilmington, North Carolina.
Today we are going to discuss maintaining a climbing rope.
Each climbing rope has a life expectancy.
When you buy your climbing rope it will tell you how many falls it can take over how much period of time.
I keep a lot on each one of my climbing ropes so I know how many times it has been outside, where I have taken it and how many falls I've taken on it so that I can retire it at the proper time.
Another really important part of maintaining your climbing rope is to inspect your rope each and every time that you take it out of the bag.
Speaking of the bag you want to keep it in a rope bag and keep it out of the dirt, out of the moisture and keep it well protected.
Climbing is inherently dangerous and can result in serious injury or death.
So inspecting your rope, maintaining your rope, keeping it clean and dry is very important.
Any time that you talk about doing this you want to make sure that you get the proper instruction on how to inspect a climbing rope and how to calculate the amount of falls it can take.
Every time that you are done with your rope you want to make sure that you put it in your climbing rope bag to keep it safe from the environment or any other things that would harm your rope like petroleum or acid.
We are going to get it folded up in there.
It rolls into the climbing rope bag which is also a great way to carry it.
This has been maintaining your climbing rope.